# **ROWAN HOLLIGAN**

UK citizen / Aufenthaltstitel until 2031 Böhmische strasse, 12055, Berlin rowanholligan@gmail.com +49 (0) 17642047887



I am an **experienced engineering manager** with a focus on **design**. I have led teams in fast-paced **agile environments developing high quality products** with a focus on B2B sales in the **tech space**. My passion for understanding and meeting my customer's needs has led me to gravitate towards **product management**. I have worked as a consultant both independantly and for one **Europe's largest** firms, developing excellent **stakeholder and project management** skills. An understanding of software development processes and web development languages round off my profile.

## **EDUCATION**

MEng Mechanical Engineering with International Studies

University of Strathclyde, Scotland 2009 - 2014

Master's Project and Thesis: "Design and Build a Wind Turbine

Universitat Politecnica de Valencia, Spain 2014 Full Stack Web Development
Career Foundry, Berlin, Germany

2023

## **KEY SKILLS**

## **Project Management & Consultancy**

- Proven ability to lead a team within multidisciplinary major projects. Experienced in planning work & deliverables, setting progress milestones and deadlines
- Experienced in waterfall and agile methods
- External (client and supplier) technical management
- · Risk identification and control
- · Project definition and scoping
- Ensuring compliance relevant directives / standards
- Team management (department and project level)

# **Design and Engineering**

- Leading complex multi discipline projects
- Design, construction and maintenance of mechanical, mechatronic, electronic, pneumatic, and hydraulic systems
- Leading end-user workshops and issue resolution
- User experience and human factors design
- Automation of product testing and quality assurance
- Functional safety design and analysis
- R&D and rapid prototyping (3D printing, hand tools, assembly)

# **Product Management**

- Feature selection, definition, and prioritisation (MVP to MLP)
- Product road mapping with stakeholders
- Authoring and maintaining product documentation
- Competitor and market analysis
- Issue resolution and prioritisation (5 WHYs)
- Customer feedback gathering, on-site workshops to identify critical needs and product issue identification
- Data driven approach to feature and issue prioritisation
- Budget management (PCM)

#### **Product Standards and Directives**

- Responsible for the identification, selection and prioritisation of the directives and standards relevant to the product.
- Led product compliance with EU directives for CE marking: Machinery, EMC, Noise, and Radio Equipment.
- Significant experience with the following harmonised product, safety and EMC standards: ISO 12100, ISO 13849, IEC 62061, IEC 60335, ISO 3691-4, IEC 60204, IEC 61000, etc.
- Compliance with UK nuclear regulatory assessment

### **SOFTWARE**

#### PM + Docs

JIRA / Asana / Shortcut Trello / Ora Confluence / Notion

#### Office

MS Office MS Project MS Visio

#### **Programming**

HTML5 / CSS3
Javascript / React
Node.js
SQL

## **Engineering**

Solidworks Solidworks PDM Inventor / Fusion ANSYS

## **LANGUAGES**

English (Native) German (B2) French (Basic) Spanish (Basic)

# **SELECTED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Self employed (2022-2023), Berlin DE

ROLE	PROJECT AND RESPONSIBILITIES	ACHIEVEMENTS
Design and business consultancy	<ul> <li>Engineering consultancy to startups and established business</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Client cost reductions related to EMC compliance</li> </ul>
2023	Due diligence design assessment	Rapid delivery of projects to client needs

ROLE	PROJECT AND RESPONSIBILITIES	ACHIEVEMENTS
Head of Hardware Engineering 2019 - 2022	<ul> <li>Overall responsibility for product development (hardware, PLC &amp; embedded software, UX) of an autonomous electrical industrial sweeper robot (lead)</li> <li>Product management (hardware, embedded software, UX, customer support)</li> <li>CE and safety certification (lead)</li> <li>Product vision and market research and workshops with leadership</li> <li>Issue resolution and QA for deployments and production (lead)</li> <li>Leadership of department and feature level teams</li> <li>Management of design and production teams (circ. 15 people)</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Rapid prototype development and deployment for initial customer testing and feedback</li> <li>Complete design cycle to series production in 18 months</li> <li>CE certification of the product in 18 months (including testing to ISO 61000 / IEC 62061)</li> <li>60% reduction in customer issue reports by identifying and implenting critical fixes between prototype and series production</li> <li>80% reduction in on-site commissioning time through process automation and simplification</li> <li>40% reduction in production cost through feature prioritisation and part homogenisation</li> </ul>
Self employed (2017	-2019), Berlin DE	
ROLE	PROJECT AND RESPONSIBILITIES	ACHIEVEMENTS
Design and business consultancy 2017 - 2019	Business and technical support to robotics startup (Berlin)	Rapid prototype development and build for
	Detailed HVAC design for sports centre (UK)	initial start-up project

• Independent delivery of HVAC designs

# WS Atkins (2014-2017), Bristol UK

2017 - 2019

ROLE	PROJECT AND RESPONSIBILITIES	ACHIEVEMENTS
Mechanical design consultant DEC 2016	<ul> <li>Critical Assembly Building Design Evaluation</li> <li>Design optimisation of existing systems to increase range of motion of overhead crane</li> </ul>	Increased crane range of motion by >60% in key zones & reduced energy consumption
Mechanical design consultant SEP - DEC 2016	<ul> <li>Furnace Process Building Detailed Design (RIBA Stage 4b)</li> <li>Completed design of process cooling and ventilation systems (normal and emergency), HVAC, and plumbing systems</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Completed 3D Revit model to stage 4b requirements</li> <li>Project delivered on time, to budgetary and quality requirements</li> </ul>
Mechanical design team lead JAN - DEC 2016	<ul> <li>Main Site Command Facility Detailed Design (RIBA Stage 4a)</li> <li>Responsible for all mechanical systems and deliverables and liason with the project director and client authority</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Responsible for delivery of £3.2m mechanical services. Won £80k for advanced delivery of mechanical long lead items</li> <li>Received bonus &amp; promotion in recognition of performance</li> </ul>
Mechanical design consultant SEP-DEC 2016	<ul> <li>The Rutherford Cancer Centre, South Wales (RIBA Stage 4a)</li> <li>Assistant designer of HVAC, medical gases, radiological assessment for proton beam therapy unit.</li> </ul>	Delivered mechanical services design for first- of-kind clinic in the UK on time and within budget
Assistant Project Manager NOV 2014 - DEC 2015	<ul> <li>Nuclear Major Projects Team</li> <li>Project management support and client team liason</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Improved project processes and compliance</li> <li>Developed data driven approach to staff oncost tracking to reduce errors in accounting</li> </ul>